st-dupont.com 2019-04-26

# S.T.Dupont | Legal terms and privacy policy

#### Identification

This site, accessible at http://www.st-dupont.com (hereinafter referred as the Website) is published by S.T. Dupont, registered in the French Register of Companies under the number B 572 230 829 with the registered offices located at 92 boulevard du Montparnasse, 75014, Paris, France.

E-mail: service-client@st-dupont.com  
Telephone number: 01 53 91 30 00  
The site publication Director: Alain Crevet 

The hosting is provided by the company NBS System SAS, whose registered office is at 140 Boulevard Haussmann, 75008, Paris, France. Telephone number: +33 (0)1 58 56 60 80 French Register of Companies number: B 423 410 901

The technic development of S.T. Dupont website has been realized by Dn’D Agency, 23 rue Edmond Nocard 94410 - Saint Maurice, France - Phone : +33 1 48 75 59 59 - [http://www.dnd.fr](http://www.dnd.fr/ "Agence Dn'D - Agence E-commerce Magento")

#### Use of the Website

By accessing or using the Website, you fully agree to all of the terms of this Policy. If you do not agree with any of these terms, please do not use the Website. This Policy only applies to data collected on the Website.

#### Your Information

S.T. Dupont collects information about you in two ways. Firstly, S.T. Dupont collects personal information provided directly by you, such as when you register as a licensed user; participate in a survey, blog or forum; place an order; authenticate an order; e-mail S.T. Dupont; or request information from S.T. Dupont. Secondly, S.T. Dupont automatically receives information from your browser, including but not limited to your internet protocol (IP) address, information about your browser and “cookies”.

#### Cookies

Our site uses cookies to ensure that we can understand better your needs, personalise your experience and provide statistics. A cookie is a very small file sent to your web browser by a website’s server to process information more efficiently (for example, by remembering your language and/or product preferences). A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the Website uses to track the pages you have visited, however the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you provide yourself as a user. Cookies cannot read data off your hard drive, destroy files, or send viruses. Please note that third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which S.T. Dupont has no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies. 

You may object to the saving of cookies on your hard disk by configuring your browser as follows:

For Microsoft Internet Explorer 6.0 and higher:

  1. Select the “Tools” menu, then “Internet Options”.
  2. Click on the “Confidentiality” tab.
  3. Select the level required using the cursor.

For Microsoft Internet Explorer 5:

  1. Select the “Tools” menu, then “Internet Options”.
  2. Click on the “Security” tab.
  3. Select “Internet” then “Custom Level”.
  4. Click on the “Cookies” section and select the appropriate option.

For Netscape 6.x and 7.x:

  1. Select the “Edit” > ”Preferences” menu.
  2. Confidentiality and Security.
  3. Cookies.

For Firefox:

  1. Select the “Tools” > ”Options” menu.
  2. Click on the "Privacy" option.

For Safari 3.x for Mac OS X:

  1. Select the “Edit” menu.
  2. Click on the “Preferences” option.
  3. Click on the “Security” option.
  4. Click on “Display cookies”.

For Google Chrome:

  1. Click the “Tools” menu (the wrench in the upper-right corner).
  2. Select “Options”.
  3. Click the “Under the Hood” tab.
  4. Check the box “Delete cookies”.

#### Copyright & Intellectual property

All contents of this website are either Copyright © 2003 - 2016 S.T. Dupont or are licensed for use by S.T. Dupont. All rights reserved. Please refer to the section of these Terms of Use of Materials on this Website above.

#### Third party links

The Website may contain links to other websites that are owned and operated by third parties over whom S.T. Dupont has no control. When you click on one of these links, you are accessing a website that is not owned or controlled by S.T. Dupont, and you are not covered by this Privacy Policy. The inclusion of any link to such third party sites does not imply endorsement by S.T. Dupont of these sites.

#### Use of your personal information

S.T. Dupont generally uses information provided for the following reasons:

  * to enhance your experience on the Website, to improve S.T. Dupont’s products, services, communications and our relationship with you.
  * to send you information on our products, offers and events we feel may be of interest to you.
  * to gather and review statistical information.
  * for marketing research purposes relating to S.T. Dupont’s business and satisfaction surveys.
  * to protect the security or integrity of our Website, our products, our services and our business.
  * to prevent fraud and other prohibited or illegal activities.

Your Personal Information may also be used to provide you with other services you may have requested.

Any Personal Information you make available to S.T. Dupont is done so voluntarily, with your knowledge and consent when ordering products or registering for services from S.T. Dupont. We will request from you information that is mandatory (required by us to fulfill your order and meet our legal obligations) and non-mandatory (which you can give to us if you chose); if you choose not to provide the mandatory information requested then S.T. Dupont may not be able to respond to your request or activate your option choices.

#### Sharing Information within S.T. Dupont’s Group

S.T. Dupont may disclose your personal information to any member of S.T. Dupont’s group of companies, which means S.T. Dupont’s subsidiaries, S.T. Dupont’s ultimate holding company and the holding company’s subsidiaries, (as defined in section 736 of the UK Companies Act 1985).

#### Changes to the Policy

We reserve the right to modify, alter or update the Policy at any time and you agree to be bound by such modifications, alteration that might take place without notice. Any changes to S.T. Dupont’s Policy in the future will be posted on the Website and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. You are responsible for regularly reviewing the Privacy Policy for any updates and/or changes to the Privacy Policy.

#### Security

Protecting your personal information is one of the primary concerns to us. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not 100% secure or error-free, nor is it free from vulnerabilities. Although S.T. Dupont will take commercially reasonable steps to protect your personal data, S.T. Dupont cannot guarantee the security of any data transmitted to S.T. Dupont’s Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once the information received, S.T. Dupont will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access, misuse or alteration of your personal information. S.T. Dupont is not responsible for the actions of third parties.

#### Storage of data

S.T. Dupont may be required to retain your personal information for a reasonable period as long as the law requires.
